Class of 1940 Records, 1936-2002
Smith College Archives
Class of 1940 Records
1936-2002
Smith College. Class of 1940.
RG 80
8 boxes (4.25 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1940.
Historical Note
The Class of 1940 was the sixty-second graduating class of Smith College.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Class of 1940 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1940, including materials from commencement, reunions, senior dramatics, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, letters, questionnaires, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1940 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class Animal 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 1)
- Commencement 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 2)
- Commencement 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 3)
- Commencement-Music 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 4)
- Commencement-Photographs 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 5)
- Commencement-Photographs 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 6)
- Commencement Speaker 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 7)
- Freshman Handbook 1936-1937 (Box 2119, Folder 8)
- Class Gift to Mrs. Morrow 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 9)
- Groups 1936-1940 (Box 2119, Folder 10)
- Hoop Rolling 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 11)
- Ivy Day 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 12)
- Ivy Day-Photographs 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 13)
- Junior Prom 1939 (Box 2119, Folder 14)
- Junior Ushers 1939 (Box 2119, Folder 15)
- Last Chapel 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 16)
- Last Sing 1940 (Box 2119, Folder 17)
- Class Letters 1955-2002 (Box 2119, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous 1936-1940, n.d. (Box 2119, Folder 19)
- Secretary's Records-Correspondence 1956-1990 (Box 2119, Folder 20)
- Secretary's Records-Financial Information 1957-1988 (Box 2119, Folder 21)
- Secretary's Records-Information for Class Secretaries 1980, 1990, n.d. (Box 2119, Folder 22)
- Secretary's Records-Minutes of Class Officer's Meetings 1960, 1965-1970, 1988 (Box 2119, Folder 23)
- Secretary's Records-Class News Cards 1955-1970 (Box 2119, Folder 24)
- Secretary's Records-Class Newsletters 1957-1990 (Box 2119, Folder 25)
- Secretary's Records-Reports for Class Meetings 1955-1990 (Box 2119, Folder 26)
- Secretary's Records-Reunions 1965-1975 (Box 2119, Folder 27)
- Mademoiselle Magazine Questionnaire 1950 (Box 2120, Folder 1)
- Officers 1936-1940 (Box 2120, Folder 2)
- Photographs 1936 (Box 2120, Folder 3)
- Reunions 1941 (Box 2120, Folder 4)
- Reunions 1945 (Box 2120, Folder 5)
- Reunions 1950 (Box 2120, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1955 (Box 2120, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1960 (Box 2120, Folder 8)
- Reunions 1965 (Box 2120, Folder 9)
- Reunions 1970 (Box 2120, Folder 10)
- Reunions 1975 (Box 2120, Folder 11)
- Reunions 1980 (Box 2120, Folder 12)
- Reunions 1985 (Box 2120, Folder 13)
- Reunions 1990 (Box 2120, Folder 14)
- Reunions 1995 (Box 2120, Folder 15)
- Senior Dinner Dance 1940 (Box 2120, Folder 16)
- Senior Dramatics 1940 (Box 2120, Folder 17)
- Senior Prom 1940 (Box 2120, Folder 18)
- Senior Statistics 1940 (Box 2120, Folder 19)
- Songs n.d. (Box 2120, Folder 20)
- Sophomore Carnival 1938 (Box 2120, Folder 21)
- Sophomore Push Committee 1938 (Box 2120, Folder 22)
- Step Sings 1940 (Box 2120, Folder 23)
- Class Supper 1940 (Box 2120, Folder 24)
- Year Book 1940 (Box 2120, Folder 25)
- Secretary's Class File (Box OV)